acdsee.com 2013-06-27

# Privacy Policy - ACD Systems

We are committed to protecting your privacy and the security of information you provide to us. ACD Systems International Inc. ("ACD") will not sell, rent, lease or disclose customer information to third parties unless required by law or unless you provide consent to such a disclosure. Other terms of ACD's privacy policy are as follows:

### Information Collection

When you engage in activities on our websites or within our products, like ordering or registering products, downloading trial versions of software or software updates, requesting technical support, or subscribing to newsletters and e-mail publications, ACD may ask you to provide us with information. By choosing to enter and submit the requested information when prompted, you are consenting to ACD's collection, use, and disclosure of such information for the purposes of providing the services to you as outlined herein. Any information you post to a chat room or public bulletin is available to all users of that site.

### Website Analytics

We use Google Analytics, Google AdWords Conversion tracker, and other Google services that place cookies on a browser across the website. These cookies help us increase the website’s effectiveness for our visitors. These cookies are set and read by Google. To opt out of Google tracking, please visit this [page](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

We use AdWords remarketing to market our sites across the web. We place a cookie on a browser, and then a 3rd party (Google) reads these cookies and may serve an ad on a 3rd party site. You may opt out of this ad serving on [Google’s opt out page](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html). If you are concerned about 3rd party cookies served by networks, you should also visit the [Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

### How We Use Your Information

Any information collected will be used only by ACD to improve our products, services and websites, or to communicate with you by phone, e-mail, newsletter, and/or notices. ACD uses information and/or e-mail addresses for internal purposes only and does not sell, lease or rent information to third parties.

### Trial Software Activation

A valid e-mail address is required to receive trial unlock codes for many of our products. If you enter into a trial period of ACD software, and consent to our use of your e-mail address by providing the same, we may contact you via phone or e-mail to provide additional information on our products and to survey you on your satisfaction with our software. We may also contact you to provide advance notice of termination of the trial period or an opportunity to extend your trial period. E-mail is our preferred method of communication and we value the privilege to use it.

### Product Purchasing

Information we ask you to provide when purchasing or ordering will be only the information necessary to process your purchase or order. When fulfilling an order we will ask for your name, e-mail address, address (for shipping purposes), telephone number and credit card number, type and expiration date (if paying by credit card). We will use this information only for matters related to your order or product registration unless you request otherwise. Your credit card information will be maintained only for a period reasonably necessary to ensure payment has been received.

### Product Registration

If, after or during purchase, you choose to register your ACD software, any information you provide will only be used to improve the service provided to you as a result of your registration. The details of information we gather will be used to uniquely identify your relationship to an ACD software application and potentially to support communication with you including: notification of software updates and service releases, notice of changes in policy that relate to the use of your software, and the provision to you of prioritized customer service or technical support.

### ACD Newsletter and Information List Memberships

When you consent to receive newsletters, ACD may use information it has collected to provide you with mailed or e-mailed notices according to the preferences that you indicate to us. This may include notice in the form of newsletters, website update notices, notification of the availability of new products or product updates as well as information on promotions and special offers. You can elect to not receive any further notices from ACD, either by 1) unsubscribing directly to any e-mail you receive, or 2) by logging into your account with ACD where you can unsubscribe or change your preferences. (You can log-in to the preference center once you have submitted your e-mail address to ACD and it has been processed.)

### ACD Website or ACD Product User Surveys

The purpose of this information request will be optional and required only to engage in certain activities. Additional information we may ask you to provide when choosing to engage in other activities on our websites or within our products may include name, mailing address, telephone number, facsimile numbers, e-mail address, and other demographic information that will enable us to better understand the requirements of our customers and to continue to provide high quality products and services.

### Website and ACDInTouch or acdID Activity

When you visit any of ACD’s websites, some information is automatically collected, such as your computer’s operating system and browser type, version and capabilities (such as whether JavaScript is enabled and cookies are accepted), your Internet Protocol (IP) address and the time and date of your visit, the referring site (if applicable), as well as screen resolution, color and depth. This information is tracked through the use of “cookies” and “Web beacons”. Cookies are small files that are stored on your computer by your browser at the request of a website to store your personal preferences. ACD uses cookies to keep you logged in to our websites, to count the number of unique computers visiting our websites and to record your user preferences. Web beacons, or web bugs, are small graphic images on a web page or other web-based content that allow the website’s owner or a third party to monitor the IP address and other information of the websites or computer viewing the web page or content. Web beacons collect the IP address of the computer to which it is sent, the URL of the page from where it came and the time it was viewed. Web beacons can be linked to personal information. ACD may place Web beacons on our websites in conjunction with cookies to monitor how visitors are navigating and/or interacting with our websites. We treat automatically collected information the same was as we treat personal information if we combine it with or link to any of the personal information identified in this Privacy Policy. Otherwise, it is used in the aggregate only.

Some third parties may place cookies in advertisements and in other locations on our websites and may place Web beacons in conjunction with such cookies. Information collected by these third parties is subject to those third parties’ policies governing the use and disclosure of personal information. In addition, a third party service is used to anonymously track traffic data on our websites through the use of a cookie that is not linked to, and does not track, any personally identifiable information about the users of our websites.

Browser cookies may also be used by the ACDInTouch or acdID service when you are accessing the Internet. No personally identifiable information is transmitted across the Internet when using the ACDInTouch or acdID service (optional use from within ACD software), unless you choose to supply us with such information. Information that may be transmitted includes logging information and browser cookies. ACD may link website visitors to websites operated by third parties who are select partners of ACD. ACD attempts to select reputable partners but does not guarantee the security of any personal information disclosed on those sites.

### About Your InTouch or acdID Connection Via ACD Software

Login information is passed to the ACDInTouch or acdID server and includes such details as: connection time; Internet protocol (IP) address; application identification; host product identification (for example, informing the server that ACDInTouch or acdID is in ACDSee™); language of host application; product version (for example, what version of ACDSee is the host software); date of host install; date of server connection, and license number (if applicable).

This information is used to present you with relevant content through the ACDInTouch or acdID service and provide you with notice of the latest available upgrades and components relevant to the software you are using. The license number is used to determine if a user is entitled to product updates and whether the software is an authorized copy. Most of the information transmitted is neither unique, nor traceable to your machine. The exceptions are the client IP address and the application identification.

The client IP is necessary to establish the connection with ACD's server and is known to the server the moment you connect. The application ID is constructed from a Globally Unique Identifier (GUID). A GUID is an alphanumeric identifier used to indicate a unique installation of a product and is used in many popular software applications. An application's GUID is randomly generated the first time an ACD application is run. The application ID is generated via operating system functions, and is stored by your host application for logging.

When connecting with the ACDInTouch or acdID server, your application ID is used to uniquely identify your connection. 

### Security of Your Personal Information

ACD takes the protection of the personal information you provide very seriously. Personal information collected is stored in password-controlled servers with limited access. When passing information over the Internet through the ACDInTouch or acdID service, information is protected through the use of encryption, specifically through the use of the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. However, perfect security on the Internet does not yet exist and we cannot warrant that our transfer of data is impenetrable or invulnerable to hackers. Internal data is shared through secured transmissions and maintained in secured databases.

ACD may hire certain outside contractors to perform services or functions on our behalf (such as customer support, packaging & shipping). We will only provide those companies the personal information they need to complete the desired service. They are not permitted to use customer information for any other purpose and are obligated to keep your customer information confidential. Information submitted to ACD may be transferred across national boundaries to or from our staff in other countries. ACD will only disclose customer information if required to do so by law, legal process or if in good faith it is deemed necessary for the public interest.

### Privacy Issues and Concerns & Altering or Correcting Information

At any time you may review, alter or remove any personal information, including the permitted uses of your personal information, by contacting ACD at:

ACD Systems.  
Privacy/Customer Service  
500 Aloha St  
Suite C2-A  
Seattle, Washington  
98109  
United States of America  
Fax: 1.866.544.0291

129-1335 Bear Mountain Parkway,  
Victoria, BC, Canada   
V9B 6T9

If you have any questions or concerns regarding our online privacy policy or should you wish to withdraw your consent, contact us by e-mail at [privacy@acdsystems.com](mailto:privacy@acdsystems.com).
